<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>L I B R A R I A</title>
    <link>http://libraria.cc/</link>
    <description>Recent content on L I B R A R I A</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Libraria - CC BY-ND-SA-4.0 - Since 2015</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 11:35:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://libraria.cc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>http://libraria.cc/index.php/2022/03/12/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 11:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://libraria.cc/index.php/2022/03/12/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employment</title>
      <link>http://libraria.cc/employment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 09:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://libraria.cc/employment/</guid>
      <description>JOB OPENING: P/T COMMUNITY CONVENER MAY 1-OCTOBER 31, 2022 | REMOTE POSITION Libraria is a collective of researchers based in the social sciences who seek to bring about a more open, diverse, community-controlled scholarly communication system. We invite applications for a part-time convener to help build a community of practice among scholar-led, “diamond” (APC-free) open access publications in anthropology and adjacent fields. The convener will build on the findings and recommendations of Libraria’s 2021 report, Exploring Mutuality: A Report on Independent Open Access Publications in the Social Sciences, as part of Libraria’s Cooperate for Open initiative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooperate for Open Report</title>
      <link>http://libraria.cc/resources/cooperate-for-open-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 07:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://libraria.cc/resources/cooperate-for-open-report/</guid>
      <description>We are delighted to present the results of our Cooperate for Open feasibility study. The full report is available for download here: http://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4795689
In early 2020, Libraria received support from a group of U.S. research libraries to pursue a feasibility study for the Cooperate for Open project. The project, which focused on born-OA, diamond OA, and/or scholar-led open access publications in anthropology and adjacent fields, aimed to identify a model for sustaining these publications, while reducing the risk and workload often associated with this segment of the publishing landscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Executive Committee</title>
      <link>http://libraria.cc/team/executive-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:16:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://libraria.cc/team/executive-committee/</guid>
      <description>Kirsten Bell is Professor of Social Anthropology in the Department of Life Sciences at the University of Roehampton. She has published widely on the anthropology of public health and her most recent book is Health and Other Unassailable Values: Reconfigurations of Health, Evidence and Ethics (Routledge, 2017). Her five-year editorial stint with a commercially-published academic journal stimulated an interest in open access and led to her decision to complete a Master of Publishing at Simon Fraser University to explore alternative models of scholarly publishing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advisory &amp; Oversight Board</title>
      <link>http://libraria.cc/team/advisory-oversight-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://libraria.cc/team/advisory-oversight-board/</guid>
      <description>Curtis Brundy, Associate University Librarian for Scholarly Communications and Collections, Iowa State University
Joe Goetz, Information Literacy Librarian, Subject Librarian for Anthropology and English, Fondren Library, Rice University
Deborah Lenares, Senior Analyst and Strategist for Collections and Budget, MIT Libraries
Paolo Mangiafico, Scholarly Communications Strategist, Duke University Libraries
Andrée Rathemacher, Professor &amp;amp; Head, Acquisitions, University Libraries, University of Rhode Island
Alison Scott, Associate University Librarian for Collection Management &amp;amp; Scholarly Communication, UCLA Library</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooperate for Open</title>
      <link>http://libraria.cc/program-areas/cooperate-for-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 14:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://libraria.cc/program-areas/cooperate-for-open/</guid>
      <description>We have recently set up a new demonstration workspace where we wish to explore how to leverage our relations with libraries and funders to help small OA operations develop sustainable cooperative long-term publishing strategies.
We are particularly interested in designing experimental cooperative frameworks for existing open access, trans-national STS publications which, for reasons of scale, resources, and the lack of reliable services/partnerships from publishers, find it particularly difficult to get a foothold in our prevalent culture of metrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scholarly Societies</title>
      <link>http://libraria.cc/program-areas/scholarly-societies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 14:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://libraria.cc/program-areas/scholarly-societies/</guid>
      <description>Since our foundation Libraria has liaised with, advocated for, as well as designed and developed ad-hoc financial and business models to help flip the journals portfolios of various scholarly societies, including the American Anthropological Association, the European Association of Social Anthropologists, the European Association of Archaeologists and the Society for Social Studies of Science (4S), amongst others.
Some of our published work on this front includes:
 Why an Open Access Publishing Cooperative can Work https://doi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Access for Anthropology: A Model for Universal OA</title>
      <link>http://libraria.cc/index.php/2019/02/01/open-access-for-anthropology-a-model-for-universal-oa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 09:33:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://libraria.cc/index.php/2019/02/01/open-access-for-anthropology-a-model-for-universal-oa/</guid>
      <description>We are delighted to announce that we are organizing an invitational workshop on “Open Access for Anthropology: A Model for Universal OA” to be held April 24th, 2019 at MIT. At the workshop we shall present the model of a pilot project we have agreed to develop in partnership with Berghahn journals and select titles from their anthropology portfolio.
The workshop will bring together journal editors, societies, publishers, and funders in the area of anthropology, along with representatives of the research libraries and strategic advisors, to explore the potential of combining two very promising OA approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscribe-to-Open</title>
      <link>http://libraria.cc/program-areas/subscribe-to-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 23:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://libraria.cc/program-areas/subscribe-to-open/</guid>
      <description>Libraria is an open access initiative formed in 2015 by an international group of researchers in the social sciences who are committed to helping scholarly societies and publishers adopt open access publishing models. After exploring a number of strategies, it is now working on a very promising subscribe-to-open (S2O) approach to converting subscription journals to open access. The model builds on a tradition of academic libraries’ support for open access, which has found fruitful expression in such initiatives as SCOAP3, Open Library of the Humanities, and Knowledge Unlatched.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://libraria.cc/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 20:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://libraria.cc/about/</guid>
      <description>Libraria is a collective of researchers based in the social sciences who, drawing on the expertise of librarians, publishers, and other stakeholders, seek to bring about a more open, diverse, community-controlled scholarly communication system.
Established in 2015, Libraria has evolved into a consulting and advocacy network that aims to convene informed conversations and catalyze demonstration projects. Our partnership with the Public Knowledge Project allows us to accept financial support from organizations aligned with our mission and to make targeted investments in the future we hope to help realize.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to LIBRARIA</title>
      <link>http://libraria.cc/index.php/2015/07/20/welcome-to-libraria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 15:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://libraria.cc/index.php/2015/07/20/welcome-to-libraria/</guid>
      <description>LIBRARIA is a collective of anthropology, archaeology and social studies of science journals and learned societies that have teamed with the Public Knowledge Projectand the Scholarly Publishing and Academic Resources Coalition (SPARC), two of world’s leading experts in open access scholarly communications, to research cooperative alternatives to the existing ecology of academic publishing.
You can read more about LIBRARIA, including a list of our current members, here. You can find out more about our aims and objectives here, and about the Open Access Cooperative Publishing Study of which we are a part here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
